How can you two be so sure
that it's not an affair?
You were so suspicious of me and Mrs. Sonoda.
[Episode 7]
We met at the laundromat,
and we just talked
until the laundry was done.
I think it's the same thing.
You're right.
Sorry about your cheek. Here's some ice.
Thanks.
I'm sorry for taking up your time.
I'm sorry.
No problem.
- Let me just confirm everything.
- All right.
Your relationship with my wife was just
talking at the laundromat once a month.
- Yes.
- You went to Nagano
to see your estranged parents.
- Yes.
- And you invited my wife to go along.
Yes.
At the service area,
you got off the bus alone.
And then you disappeared without going home.
Yes.
Well, I'm curious about the reason, but...
It's none of my business,
and you don't have to tell me.
- But still...
- I've left Sho with Mr. Miyauchi,
so I shouldn't be too late.
Right.
Well, then...
Can we talk on the way? Just the two of us.
All right.
See you later.
I'm sorry.
What happened to your wife...
it was my fault.
I'm sorry.
I won't hit you.
Even though you probably want me to.
About the disappearance... it's a long story.
No, it's fine. It really doesn't matter.
Actually, I don't care.
I don't care about anything except Azusa!
I think there were things I lacked.
So instead of talking to me at home,
she went out of her way to go do laundry,
just to talk to you.
But we've lived together in the same house,
just the two or three of us,
and I think I understand Azusa pretty well.
What? Really?
Did you really ask Azusa to go with you?
Yes.
It was all my fault. I dragged her into it.
Hello, it's me.
Thank you for everything.
Ah, your ride is here.
Wait just a second, Daddy.
I'm at a good part.
I'm sorry, we're right in the middle
of a good part here.
Okay, I'll wait.
The tail goes whoosh, and then smack!
It's fun, right?
Sorry, I'll be waiting outside.
Okay.
I'm home.
Sacchan.
I'm back.
Sacchan?
Sacchan? Sacchan!
What's wrong?
Oh, you were in the bathroom?
Yeah.
Huh? Why were you panicking? What happened?
Did someone hit you? Do you need ice?
Nobody hit me. I'm fine.
What is it? What happened?
I thought you were gone.
What?
You were panicking
because you thought I was gone?
Yeah.
Just because you couldn't
find me for a few seconds?
Yeah.
Someone who disappeared for a year
doesn't have any right to worry like that.
I'm sorry.
I'm the one who suspected you,
so I have no right, but...
I even thought that maybe it would have been
better if you had been cheating.
Because inviting her to go with you
for something like that...
That's a pretty
deep level of trust, isn't it?
When we got married, we decided
that it's okay to not talk about things
we don't want to.
Yeah.
If I told you, you might hate me.
There are a lot of things
I'm too scared to say.
But I'll tell you. Otherwise...
I can't explain why I ran away,
or what happened with Mrs. Sonoda.
I'll go get the laundry.
Yeah.
That there, I gave it to him. It's Azusa's.
- Here.
- Oh, yes.
I gave this to Azusa.
Before we got married.
Maybe it was on her birthday?
Yeah.
It matches the book cover.
Wait, how do you know?
Ah.
She said she really liked these.
That bookmark, and also this.
I never saw it at home.
I thought she'd lost it.
Then take it home.
Thank you.
Her things just keep turning up, don't they?
Even after a year.
[Sho stubbed his little toe
on the table leg and was hurting]
[I witnessed Sho's first time stubbing his
little toe on a table leg and being in pain]
Since that husband seems to be back,
I thought it would be okay
for me to give this to you now.
No, no, you should look at it.
There wasn't anything written in there
that would shock you.
Oh sorry, I read it.
I know now that she wasn't having an affair.
But... that's actually why I'm shocked.
Huh?
A trust that's separate
from romantic feelings...
Isn't that just too strong?
How much have I told you about my parents?
That you went to a high school
that had a dormitory for its swimming club,
and after that, you and your parents
gradually grew apart. That's all.
Yeah.
The last time I saw them
was reluctantly when
I got into college, for scholarship stuff.
So it's been about twenty years.
I see.
My parents didn't want kids.
But they had me,
so they got married, I guess.
I didn't hear that directly.
I just overheard relatives
talking about it over drinks.
Kids can tell, you know,
when adults are like that.
- Hello.
Mitsuru, you're looking well.
Sometimes there are poor kids
who need adults other than their parents
to protect them,
but I wasn't like that.
I had food to eat.
I could take baths.
My clothes were washed.
I wasn't hit or kicked.
I just... wasn't loved.
Not loving your child isn't against the law.
So I lived with my parents.
Until nursery school, I wanted attention,
so I acted out
and tried my best to get attention.
But they never got angry.
They'd just sigh or glare.
After I started elementary school,
I made friends and listened to my teachers.
If I was a good kid, my mom wouldn't sigh,
and she wouldn't glare.
The thing I was most surprised
to learn at school
was that birthdays
are meant to be celebrated.
When did you learn that?
Did you have candles on a cake
at home for your birthday?
I was born in Tokyo, apparently,
but because of my dad's job,
ever since I could remember,
we moved very frequently.
I don't even know how many times
I transferred schools.
I remember you said that
you didn't have a family home.
No hometown, no childhood friends,
nothing like that.
And no fixed place to go back to either.
- That must have been hard.
- Not really.
It was actually good
that it was that kind of family.
In the town we moved to
in the winter of first grade,
there was a coffee shop that my mom liked.
When she was in a good mood, she'd take me.
Mom, the cake was delicious.
There were things
other than strawberries in it too.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Do you like trains?
Yes.
Here.
I'm not giving it to you,
but you can look at it and touch it.
There were things
other than strawberries in the cake.
Yeah, like kiwi and orange.
Even though it was a strawberry shortcake?
[Today's Cake: Strawberry Shortcake]
A strawberry, kiwi, and orange shortcake.
Saying all that would be a mouthful, right?
Right? And it'd also be a pain
to write all that out.
That shop owner was an adult
who listened to me.
I told him everything.
Things my mom wouldn't listen to,
and things I couldn't tell my teacher
because I was trying to be a good kid.
That I rooted for the villains
more than the heroes in anime.
That to make sure
I wouldn't eat too much at home,
I'd get seconds at school lunch,
even when I was full.
That I'd miss my stop on purpose
and go on adventures to the bus stop
two stops further away.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Delicious.
- Delicious?
When it was decided that
we would be moving again...
[Thank you
Mitsuru Seo]
on the day before we moved,
I went alone to the coffee shop
and told the owner.
You don't need to be attached
to one place or one person.
From now on, you can go anywhere.
You'll meet all kinds of people.
He didn't seem sad.
I thought he was a bit cold-hearted,
but it also made me feel better.
[Thank you
Mitsuru Seo]
That I didn't have to stay in one place.
That night...
I ran away for the first time in my life.
You ran away?
I just took random trains
to go as far away as I could.
And after the last train had left,
I slept on a bench in a park
in a strange town.
I hitched a ride on a truck
and crossed prefectural borders.
Well, I was just eight years old.
People thought I got lost
and took me into protective custody.
My parents didn't get mad.
They were just worried about appearances,
and told me not to cause any more trouble.
But the thrill of going far away
without anyone knowing, without a purpose...
I couldn't stop.
During a field trip in fourth grade,
during a school trip
to the beach in sixth grade,
during a club trip in eighth grade,
in the middle of a date
with my girlfriend in eleventh grade,
in my first year of college,
the morning after summer break...
I'd just vanish
and go completely off the grid.
In terms of feelings,
it's a desire to escape.
In modern terms, it's like
'relationship reset syndrome.'
The easiest way to put it is
a 'disappearing habit.'
Disappearing habit...
That's why I was grateful
for my family's constant moving.
Because I didn't have to belong
to a community for long.
But family is strange, isn't it?
Why do they keep living together
even after moving?
I'd run away every two or three years,
and when I grew up,
I'd switch jobs each time.
Right after I met you,
there was a time when
I went off the grid, remember?
Yeah, about three months.
You said it was for a business trip abroad.
That was a lie.
That was my last disappearance,
until this one.
By then I'd already quit my previous job
and reset all my relationships.
Finding a new job was getting harder,
so I thought I'd do something on my own,
and that's the current coffee shop.
I told you I wanted to own my own shop,
so I lied about quitting my previous job.
But actually, it was the other way around.
I had no idea.
I suppose I'm probably a good liar.
Because ever since I can remember,
everything was a lie.
It was before we got married,
but I'm sorry for the lie.
I'm such an idiot.
During the time I couldn't reach you,
I was lonely,
and I became sure that I really loved you.
That's what I thought during that time.
Me too.
But you were the one who disappeared.
When I run away,
I aim for places
where I won't see anyone I know.
But that time, for the first time,
I thought, I want to see her.
Sakiko Nakabayashi...
I wonder how she's doing?
I ignored your messages for three months,
so I thought you might hate me.
I got anxious.
For the first time, I wanted to see someone.
"Sorry for the delay."
"I just got back from
an overseas business trip."
"I'd love to see you again."
You remember a LINE message
from ten years ago?
Yes, I remember.
I was so happy I took a screenshot.
I'm sorry about the lie.
Wanting to see you was real, though.
Let's put this away. Want to take a bath?
Okay, but I want to hear everything first.
Okay.
[April 28 (Sun)
While I was folding the laundry,]
[Sho said on his own that
he wanted to help out.]
[A good man, just like his dad.]
[Seems he has a crush at nursery school.
He won't tell me, but it's probably Moka.]
[Happy, but also a bit complicated.]
[Right after waking up, he said,
"Morning! Yesterday was so fun."]
[I had no idea what he was talking about,
but apparently he went swimming in his dream.]
[He had fun because he got three ice creams
on the way back from swimming...]
That's Mom's handwriting.
- It's Mom's handwriting, right? Read it.
- Yeah. What's wrong?
Did you wake up? Need the bathroom?
- Read it, what Mom wrote.
- Okay.
Later, okay?
Let's go back to sleep for now.
Will you read it later?
Yeah, I'll read it later.
I turned on the AC in the bedroom.
Hey.
You said just now that you'd run away
every two or three years.
Yeah.
But it's been about ten years since then.
We started dating pretty soon after that,
got married, and have been
together ever since.
You're amazing, Sacchan.
You kept me in the same place for ten years.
Then why did you do it again?
A child.
We realized it would be
difficult to have one,
so we decided to stop treatment
and buy a house, right? You wanted that.
- Yeah.
- I'd never lived in a house before.
So I was looking forward to it,
and it was fun deciding things together.
Wow!
This feels good.
But the moment I stepped inside, I thought,
it's going to be the two of us here forever.
I can't run away anymore.
I thought it was just my imagination,
but once we started living here,
I wanted to run away more and more.
I'd get on the wrong bus or train on purpose,
trying to get taken somewhere I didn't know.
There were signs like that, and it scared me.
It's not like I dislike you.
But just the two of us,
in the same place forever...
The more I thought about it,
the more I felt suffocated by happiness.
Even if I explain it,
it probably doesn't make sense.
Even if I say I don't hate you,
you'd suspect that would mean
that I love someone else.
It's always sudden.
There's no planning for tomorrow.
That day was the same, at the service area.
I thought, now's the time.
I'll just disappear.
I never thought the bus
would get into an accident.
I took advantage of Mrs. Sonoda
and got off alone.
- I don't think you'll understand, but...
- I understand.
I understand that you're that kind of person.
I understand your past too.
And I believe all of it.
Yeah.
So...
What should I have done?
What should I have done
to make you come back sooner?
You've never done anything wrong.
With everyone I've met before,
I've always assumed that
the connection would eventually break.
But you were different.
I didn't know what to do.
I want to be with you,
but the real me is like this.
I was always scared you'd hate me,
and you'd disappear.
I was always scared.
So you'd rather disappear yourself
before that happens?
I started thinking that way,
but I managed not to run away.
Why?
Because on the third Friday of every month,
I could see Mrs. Sonoda.
Friday, June 21, 2024.
I wanted to wash all my summer clothes
that smelled musty from the closet,
so I went to a nearby laundromat.
That's where I met Mr. Seo.
About a year before the accident,
I wanted to wash all the stuff from the shop,
so I went to a nearby laundromat,
and that's where I met Mrs. Sonoda.
What next?
Excuse me.
Well... how do I operate this?
I want to dry some clothes.
- With cash?
- Oh, yes, cash.
- So you put the money in here...
- And then, the money.
- I see. Thank you.
- No problem.
Do you come here often?
- Me?
- Yes.
No, it's my first time here.
Did your washing machine break?
No, I'm just washing some things
that I use for work.
And there was quite a lot.
Would your wife get mad
if you washed stuff from work at home?
No, she wouldn't get mad.
It's just that there was a lot to wash.
I see.
How did you know that I'm married?
Oh, the ring.
Are you reading a book?
- Yes.
- I thought so.
You mean, is it okay if you talk to me?
Yes.
I'm just reading to kill time, so it's fine.
So, is it okay if we chat?
Okay, until my laundry is done.
Thank you.
Okay, what next? What should we talk about?
- Mrs. Sonoda was a strange person.
- Hmm, what to talk about?
She wanted to talk to a stranger
- she didn't need to talk to.
- What to talk about?
She went out of her way to chat.
I didn't get it.
Let's see.
Something I can't tell my husband
would be good.
I usually tell my husband everything.
- I see.
- Ah.
How much would you spend on a T-shirt?
You know, a plain white one.
- Maybe 3,000 yen?
- Right, right.
My husband would spend up to 15,000 yen
on a white T-shirt.
What do you think?
Well, I think it's up to you
where you spend your money.
If it's not hurting the household budget,
- and it's just your husband's preference...
- No, no, it's fine.
This is just chitchat.
This isn't work or school.
Give me your honest opinion.
We probably won't see each other again.
Even in the worst case scenario,
being hated wouldn't really matter either.
Would you feel hurt if I hated you?
- No.
- See?
That's why I love talking to people
who have nothing to do with my life.
I think 15,000 yen is really expensive.
See? You do think it's expensive.
Don't lie to me.
Sorry.
And, as you'd expect from spending that much,
he's really particular about it.
There are so many shades of white.
You know that famous quote, right?
Itsuki says it with a straight face,
not as a joke.
Oh right, my husband's name is Itsuki.
And then...
Mrs. Sonoda was definitely a strange person.
Whatever came to mind,
it just came out of her mouth.
She was like a completely
different creature from me.
Mr. Seo was a strange person.
He listened seriously to my silly stories,
but everything he said seemed like a lie.
I've never objected to Itsuki
spending 15,000 yen on a white T-shirt.
Not even once.
And the reason for that is...
Well, the reason is...
- Huh?
- No.
Itsuki's only hobby...
is taking walks.
- Really?
- I mean,
a man in his mid-thirties
whose hobby is walking...
Wouldn't you think that he's boring?
What's wrong with walking?
Right? It's nice.
It's free, and it's good for one's health.
He takes Sho to the park and stuff.
Sho is my son, he's four.
Sho, like Shohei Ohtani.
And when he goes to the park with Sho...
Even when I thought it was going to be
a complaint about her husband,
it always ended up being a lovey-dovey story.
I think she really loves her husband
and can't help it.
Oh, do you have weekdays off? Today's Friday.
I run a coffee shop
and Fridays are my regular day off.
Wow, that's nice, having your own shop.
I work part-time at a used bookstore,
and on Fridays, another part-timer can cover,
so I usually have the day off.
I love having days off on weekdays.
Itsuki's at work,
and Sho's at nursery school.
I love the time we spend together
as a family of three,
but that's probably
because I can get away from them on Fridays.
Ah... I get it.
Well, maybe this is it.
I want to be with Sacchan, and it's fun,
but being together all the time is hard.
That's why I don't want to change my day off.
- Oh.
- Sacchan...
Your wife?
- Yes.
- Huh?
Why do you look so guilty?
- No...
- No, I mean,
it's normal to feel that way about your wife.
I feel that way not just
about my husband, but my kid too.
Sometimes I just want to get away.
Even though I love them so much.
Is that how it is?
Yes.
I see.
What's it like being a parent?
Sho...
He's very precious to me, and I love him.
I'm glad I had him.
Want something to drink?
No, I'm fine.
I don't have parents, so I lack role models.
Oh, but that does have its own advantages.
Having a clear idea of what a perfect mother
is supposed to be must be tough too.
I'm basically parentless too, so I get it.
Did they pass away?
Or were you in an institution?
No, they're around,
but they were indifferent to me as a kid.
I was dumped the moment I was born.
So I was in an institution
until I graduated from high school.
I'm a little jealous of that.
Oh, you said what you really think!
- Sorry.
- No, no, it's fine.
It's way better than
getting that 'poor you' vibe.
I mean, compared to being raised
by crappy parents,
I've had a super happy life.
You seem happy.
In an institution,
there are fewer adults than kids,
so I didn't get enough of
"Hey, Mom, listen to this."
Probably more so than kids in regular homes.
Even though you wanted someone
to listen to you.
Yes, I wanted that.
Well, the adults were all nice people.
But they couldn't always focus on me alone.
Sometimes I'd catch the guy
from the bookstore
who came to donate picture books,
and get him to listen to me.
Gosh, that must have been a nuisance for him.
What about you?
Huh?
Tell me your life story.
I like listening to other people
talk about their lives
as much as I do talking.
All right, then until the drying is done.
Okay.
I don't know if it's
because of my upbringing,
but I suddenly get the urge
to just run away from wherever I am
over and over.
A disappearing habit, I guess.
Ah, that's the most troublesome of habits.
I poured out things
I'd never told anyone before.
About my parents, the urge to run away,
always playing the nice guy,
building temporary relationships,
then running and cutting ties,
then connecting again
and running away again, over and over.
What?
Are you really going to stop talking
just because your clothes are done drying?
At this point in your story?
Can I keep talking?
Sure, go ahead.
Besides, mine's not done yet.
Our first date was a movie.
Oh, nice. Classic.
I liked movies
and often rented them to watch.
But the movie theater was tough.
We kept talking while waiting for
Mrs. Sonoda's laundry to finish drying.
She'd throw in comments,
act overly surprised,
and laugh while listening.
But she never said things like
"That's impossible" or "That's not good."
She never once said anything like that.
It's finished. Good timing.
So that was about ten years ago?
Yes.
So you're cured now?
Of the disappearing habit, I mean?
Well, because Sacchan has been here
these last ten years.
Another lovey-dovey story.
But it doesn't feel like it's cured.
So you still want to run away, huh?
Yes.
The towels are fluffy.
Itsuki will be happy.
He likes thick, fluffy, soft towels.
- Is that so?
- Yes.
Our place is right here.
Oh nice, a detached house.
Sorry for talking so much.
No problem.
Well, then.
When will you next be
going to the laundromat?
When will you listen to my life story?
How about the third Friday of next month?
Got it.
And so from then on,
on the third Friday of every month,
I talked with Mrs. Sonoda
until the washing and drying was done.
We had silly small talk
and shared traumas from our childhoods
that we'd never told anyone before.
The reason I could talk to
Mrs. Sonoda about anything
was because she was a stranger
unrelated to my life,
and it didn't matter if she hated me.
- Sho finally fell asleep.
- Thanks.
- Hey, Itsuki.
- Hmm?
I'm super fast at replying to
messages on LINE, right?
Yeah, you read messages instantly.
Exactly. So if someone like me
suddenly went off the grid,
what would you think?
I'd be worried, of course.
I'd think that you'd collapsed
somewhere or something.
Or... well, that you'd lost
or broken your phone.
- Right?
- Huh?
Hey, listen to this.
Moka's mom invited me to afternoon tea.
- It's 15,000 yen per person.
- 15,000 yen?
- I blurted out "That's expensive!"
- Of course you would.
I had a baseless confidence
that I might be the only one
who could understand Mr. Seo.
Tomorrow's the third Friday of the month,
so it's the deadline.
I want to be home by ten.
I'll make dinner. What do you want?
Thanks.
Oh, but you can just
order delivery or something.
When you're alone, do whatever you want.
It's fine.
Hey, on Fridays, don't you ever
go out anywhere alone?
I do go out. Like to the laundromat,
for example.
That's just chores. Do something fun.
I like doing it. Want a beer?
Yeah.
Thanks.
- Here.
- Cheers.
As long as I had that time once a month,
I wouldn't run away from here.
I wouldn't feel anxious about
the happiness right in front of me.
It was a time
for me to distance myself from the people
I'd be with for the rest of my life,
and at the same time,
a time to reaffirm my happiness
of being with them.
Even though I wanted to be
a little bit apart from them,
we mostly still just talked about
the people we lived with.
For me,
he was just someone
who listened to me once a month.
And that was nice.
I'm not doing anything wrong,
but it's still hard to tell Itsuki
about Mr. Seo.
[I'm not confident that Itsuki would
understand my relationship with Mr. Seo.]
You could call it friends or neighbors,
maybe there's a name for it,
but my relationship
with Mrs. Sonoda was like that.
With you, we decided that we didn't
have to talk about things we didn't want to,
and that was comfortable.
But with Mrs. Sonoda, I could say anything,
and it didn't matter if she hated me.
Yeah, okay, I get it.
I kept quiet because I wasn't confident
that you'd understand.
I thought that no matter how
I explained it, it would upset you,
and that you'd suspect me.
Someone whom you don't care
if they hate you. I see.
And I'm someone whom
you don't want to hate you.
Yeah.
Oh.
Like something you don't want to get dirty,
even though it's your favorite outfit.
And so you never wear it, right?
While something that
you splatter meat sauce all over,
eating pasta while wearing,
and saying "This is delicious"
feels more like family.
If it gets dirty, just wash it.
I'm not good at doing laundry,
but I am pretty good at getting stains out.
I know.
You know that I'm good at getting stains out?
I know that I was
getting it wrong little by little.
I'd throw things away before they got dirty
and then buy new ones.
That's how I've lived my life.
But when I didn't want to get it dirty
and also didn't want to throw it away,
I didn't know what to do.
- Wait.
- Wait?
That's not fair! You're the one who...
I have times when I want to
get away from here too, you know.
Maybe for just a few seconds, maybe a year.
She wasn't someone
completely unrelated to your life.
You took her to meet your parents.
You're leaving now? Where are you going?
To Mrs. Sonoda's husband's place?
So what if I am?
Can you say "Don't go"?
Your name...
Okay you two, your luggage first...
[3-4-4 Minamisensu, Minami-Shinshu,
Nagano Prefecture]
Good morning.
- Huh?
- Nice weather we're having here today.
A little too hot, though.
What are you doing here?
Today's the day Miki is coming over.
Oh, she's my sister-in-law.
My husband's sister.
She's going to watch Sho for me.
That's not what I meant.
I might actually want to tag along.
Aren't you feeling a little uneasy?
But this isn't any of your business,
Mrs. Sonoda.
If it's not any of my business,
then what's the harm
in you inconveniencing me a little?
As I was hearing about
your history of disappearing, Mr. Seo,
I found myself getting
more and more intrigued.
No way. Disappearing is a bad idea.
Absolutely not.
- It'd cause trouble for your family.
- Oh, no, no.
I wouldn't do a real disappearing act.
I have a husband and a child,
and a home to return to. That's my happiness.
Then that's even more reason.
It sounds like
you haven't exactly kicked the habit.
Right.
So I figured that maybe a little
pressure release would do you good.
- A one-day disappearance, just for today?
- Exactly.
If I get home before
anyone realizes I'm gone,
then it technically never happened.
And since we already chat once a month,
how about a mini-disappearance
every six months or so?
I like it.
Although some people
might call that having an affair.
Ah, yeah.
Well, isn't that okay?
A little bit of guilt like this is worth it,
even if we only talk once a month.
And even just that,
some people would still make a fuss
and call it an emotional affair.
If they'll never understand us anyway,
then let's just do something
a little scandalous.
You're right.
We will be departing shortly.
- Please hurry.
- It's about to leave.
A one-day disappearance,
one that no one would ever know about.
I'd planned to be home by nightfall,
where Sacchan would be waiting for me.
[June 21, 2025]